

Lucas Nelaupe R&D mobile iOS and Android developer

- 25 years old
- lucas.nelaupe@gmail.com +65 8265 4423 **S** lucas34990

Award-Winning mobile developer. Graduated with a Master's degree in Computer Science major in Software architecture. 3 years + experience in ANDROID and iOS development in Singapore with cross-cultural teams.

Focusing on design, performance and productivity. Working on apps to solve real world problem.

Experience

R&D mobile iOS and Android developer

V-Cube Global Services • Singapore • Full-time • Since January 2016

- Mission: Design and develop a corporate mobile chat application
 - Android full stack development (Java / Kotlin)
 - IOS backend development (Swift)
- ► Technical aspect
 - Swift 4, Java, Kotlin
 - · Realm, SQLite, SQLCipher
 - Strong use of RxJava 2 and RxSwift
 - Offline first app: Job scheduling, cache
- Worklow flow: Jenkins CI
 - BUCK build for faster build and test
 - Unit Test (Robolectric, XCTest) and CodeCoverage
 - Static Analysis: SonarQube, SwiftLint, PMD, FindBugs, Error Prone
 - Code review with Upsource
 - Release to Beta (Fabric)
- R&C
- Travis matrix and stage build
- Keep in trying new tools, libraries and services

Android developer Intern

Massive Infinity • Singapore • Internship • March 2015 to January 2016

- Design and develop several native Android apps
- Business intelligence app for Philippe Maurice International
- Work management app for Singapore Technologies (ST)
- Worked back to back with the IOS team on internal apps

Community Manager

University Of Montpellier • Volunteer Work • 2015 to 2017

Merge duplicates and outdated pages

Hackathon Winner

Adullact • August 2014 to September 2014

- Crowdfunding application for Android
- ▶ Open source on Github licensed under Apache V2

Education

Master Degree: Architect, engineer of Software and web

University Of Montpellier • 2013 to 2015

Compilation · Metaprogramming and reflexivity · Model-driven engineering

Bachelor degree in Computer Science

University Of Montpellier • 2010 to 2013

Computer Science fundamental

Skills



Programming Languages

- ▶ Swift
- Java · Kotlin
- ▶ Javascript HTML CSS



Android

- ▶ RxJava
- ▶ SQLite, SQCipher
- ▶ Junit, Robolectric
- PMD, Checkstyle, FindBugs, Error Prone, Lint, infer
- Gradle
- Android Studio

iOS

- ▶ RxSwift
- ▶ Realm (NoSQL database)
- XCTest
- ▶ SwiftLint, taylor, tailor
- Carthage, Swift Package Manager, Cocoapods
- ▶ AppCode

Languages

- French: Native
- English: Fluent

Interests

Sports

Cycling

Travel

 Visited more than 20 countries around the world

Music

- ▶ Electronic Dance Music (EDM)
- Music festival

Open Source

- ▶ Github
- ▶ Member of Moya organisation



ADULLACT